nomorepanic.co.uk 2018-08-10

# Privacy | No More Panic

> _At No More Panic we take the privacy of our members and supporters very seriously and we are committed to protecting your privacy online.._

This statement explains the privacy and the data protection practices which apply to all websites operated by NMP. A link to this Policy is available from all websites which it applies to.

In this Policy references to NMP or to “we” or “us” are to No More Panic.

Our aim is to safeguard our users’ privacy whilst providing a personalised and valuable service. Collecting personal information is necessary if we are to satisfy the expectations and requirements of our users, e.g. by communicating with them and providing an interactive service. We appreciate that you do not want the personal information you provide to us distributed indiscriminately and here we explain how we collect information, what we do with it and what controls you have.

### We promise:

– To keep your data safe and private.  
– Not to sell your data.

### What information do we collect?

personal information such as name, postal address, telephone number, e-mail address, date of birth (where appropriate). We collect this information only in connection with specific activities, such as registration or membership requests, feedback, donations, shop purchases etc. The information is either needed to fulfil your request or to enable us to provide you with a more personalised service. You don’t have to disclose any of this information to browse our sites. However, if you do choose to withhold requested information, we may not be able to provide you with certain services.

### How is the information used?

Any personal data relating to you will be used and recorded by us in accordance with current data protection legislation and this Privacy Policy. We will use the information you provide to:

  1. fulfil your requests, for example applications for membership, donations, participation in campaigns and provision of information;
  2. process donations, or other payments and verify financial transactions;
  3. identify contributors;
  4. provide a personalised service to you when you visit our websites e.g. by customising the content and/or layout of our pages for each individual user;
  5. record any contact we have with you;
  6. prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our websites and enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf;
  7. in aggregate (and therefore anonymously) to profile your use of the websites and carry out research on our users’ demographics, interests and behaviour to help us gain a better understanding of how our users navigate and use the websites, and to enable us to improve our service to you; and
  8. provide you with information which we think may be of interest to you, as explained below.

If we contact you by email or text message, each time you receive a message you will also have the option to decline to receive further information from us in that manner.

We may disclose personal information if we receive a complaint about any content you have posted or transmitted to or from one of our sites, if required to do so by law or if we believe that such action is necessary to protect and defend the rights, property or personal safety of NMP, its sites or its visitors.

Except as indicated above we will not use or transfer this data to any third parties without your prior permission.

### Your rights

– The right to be informed about how your personal information is being used.  
– The right to access the personal information we hold about you – You can view ALL personal information in your control panel  
– The right to request the correction of inaccurate personal information we hold about you – You can amend ALL personal information in your control panel  
– The right to request that we delete your data, or stop processing it or collecting it, in some circumstances.  
– The right to stop direct marketing messages and withdraw consent for other consent-based processing at any time.  
– The right to request that we transfer or port elements of your data either to you or another service provider.  
– The right to complain to your data protection regulator — the Information Commissioner’s Office.

### For more information about your privacy rights

The Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) regulates data protection and privacy matters in the UK. They make a lot of information accessible to consumers on their website and they ensure that the registered details of all data controllers such as ourselves are available publicly. You can access them here https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public.  
You can make a complaint to the ICO at any time about the way we use your information. However, we hope that you would consider raising any issue or complaint you have with us first. Your satisfaction is extremely important to us, and we will always do our very best to solve any problems you may have.

### Sharing your information

We will not sell or rent your personal data to any third party – including your name, address, email address.

### Links

Our sites contain links to other sites. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other websites even if you access them using links from our websites and recommend that you check the policy of each site you visit.

In addition, if you linked to our websites from a third party website, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners or operators of that third party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third party site and contact its owner or operator if you have any concerns or questions.

### Advertising

No More Panic is solely funded via advertising. We use the following advertising partners

Google Adsense

PubGalaxy – [Privacy Policy](https://www.pubgalaxy.com/privacy-policy.html)

### Security

We place great importance on the security of all personally identifiable information associated with our supporters, customers and users. We have security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal data under our control. For example, our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorised personnel have access to user information. Whilst we cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of data will not occur, we use our best efforts to prevent this.

### Use of cookies

In simple terms a cookie is a small piece of information sent from our website to your computer to help us to identify you quickly. If you prefer not to accept a cookie, you can navigate around our sites like a normal user. Any information gathered by the use of cookies is compiled on an aggregate, anonymous basis.

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your hard drive to store and sometimes track information about you. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you should be able to change your browser to prevent that. You should read the information that came with your browser software to see how you can set up your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, this should then give you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it. However, you may not be able to take full advantage of a website if you do so. Cookies are specific to the server that created them and cannot be accessed by other servers, which means they cannot be used to track your movements around the web.

Cookies can be used for a variety of purposes, such as providing personalised pages, but at present, we use them only to track people visiting our sites and the pages they view on the site.

Further information about cookies can be found at the Interactive Advertising Bureau’s website [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "www.allaboutcookies.org").

### Where is the information stored?

Information which you submit via our websites is sent to a computer located in the United Kingdom. This is necessary in order to process the information and to send you the information you have requested. Information submitted by you may be transferred by us to our other offices and to other reputable third party organisations as referred to in this Policy, and these may be situated outside the European Economic Area.

### Changes

We may make changes to this Policy from time to time. If we change our Privacy Policy we will post the changes on this page. If the change in our Privacy Policy affects the use of your personal information we will use our best endeavours to contact you by email to seek your consent to the use.

### Your acceptance of this Policy

By using our sites, or by entering a competition, you consent to the collection and use of information by NMP in accordance with our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Policy, please do not use our sites or enter our competitions.

### Your rights

If you would like to review or revise information you have previously provided to us online, you may do so by emailing [nomorepanic](mailto:nomorepanic@btinternet.com).

You also have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office. Find out on their website how to report a concern <https://ico.org.uk/concerns/>
